Kelvin Kiarie Kaira

kelvinkiarie6@gmail.com

+254791025786

Nairobi, Kenya

Data Analyst

GitHub Blog Twitter

SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled data analyst with 4 years of cleaning, analyzing and drawing insights from raw data. Skilled in SQL, Python, and advanced Excel. My expertise lies in creating dashboards with Tableau and Power BI. Specializing in data transformation as well as building ETLS.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES	SKILLS	DATA STORAGE PLATFORMS	TOOLS
Python	Data profiling	AWS, Azure, Databricks, Snowflake,	Excel-Advanced
SQL	API Integration.	PostgreSQl	Power BI,Tableau
GIT	Data modelling	DATA MANAGEMENT	Seaborn, Juypter
	Excellent communication skill	Apache Airflow, Apache Kafka	Technical Writer,
	Strong analytical skill.		
	Interest in the stock market.		
	Data visualization and analysis		

EXPERIENCE

Junior Data Analyst | Kenya Revenue Authority | Nairobi, Kenya | JANUARY 2023 - DECEMBER 2024

- Developed, maintained, and enhanced dashboards and reports using Power BI, and Data Studio, improving KPI tracking efficiency by 40%.
- Documented data issues from multiple sources, ensuring 99% data accuracy and integrity across all business processes.
- Conducted in-depth financial modelling and predictive analytics, improving revenue forecasting.
- Automated reporting and data processing tasks using Python reducing manual workload.
- Achieved 10% reduction in credit defaults by implementing a predictive model, enhancing risk assessment and credit allocation decisions.

Junior Data Analyst Optica Limited | Nairobi, Kenya | Jan 2021 - Aug 2022 : Full Time

- Automated performance dashboards to track ecosystems and provide 360° oversight of key business metrics.
- Applied statistical techniques and analytical models to analyze sales patterns and performance, leading to 25% improvement in sales forecasting accuracy and identifying key growth opportunities."
- Conducted remote troubleshooting using diagnostic techniques and relevant inquiries, resolving technical issues to minimize downtime resulting in a 25% reduction in system disruptions.
- Developed SQL queries and Python scripts reducing data processing time by 30 %.
- Build an automated ETL pipeline using Airflow & PostgreSQL, hosted on cloud VM.

Freelance | Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Built sales dashboards to track key metrics, improving decision-making by 20%.
- Cleaned and organized structured large datasets, ensuring 99% accuracy.
- Designed interactive dashboards that enhanced KPI tracking efficiency helping businesses make data-driven decisions.
- Wrote SQL queries and used python for data processing, reducing processing time by 30%.
- Developed step-by-step tutorials on building dashboards and excel improving understanding to readers.
- Published technical content on SQL queries and python for data processing, helping beginners demystify key topics in data analysis
- Attended writing workshops and technical writing forums to enhance communication skills .

EDUCATION.

Bachelor of Science (Information Technology), Dedan Kimathi University of Science and Technology. Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education - Friends School Kamusinga A-

COURSE AND AWARDS.

Data Analytics Essentials, *Kenya Revenue Authority*SQL Fundamentals, Analysis in Excel, Exploratory Data Analysis in SQL
Cisco Certified Network Associate, *Dedan Kimathi University of Science and Technology*ITIL Foundation Certificate - Udemy

References.

Wairimu Njuguna, Assistant Manager, Kenya Revenue Authority

wairimu.njuguna@kra.go.ke 0720903787

Jackson Mbugua IT Manager, IT Optica.

jacksonmbugua@optica.go.ke 0713946222

Dr. John Wandeto, *Dean of Students*, Dedan Kimathi University of Science and Technology johnwandeto@gmail.com, 0733426011